popehat.com 2007-12-08

# Privacy Policy - Squarespace

Squarespace takes your privacy seriously. We will not sell, lease or exchange your personal data to third parties in ways other than described in this privacy policy. This Privacy Policy is a part of the Squarespace Terms of Service policy. By using Squarespace, including services available at the squarespace.com domains, users are using a service provided by Squarespace, Inc. and they agree to be bound by the Terms of Service and this Privacy Policy. Some terms may be defined in the Terms of Service. This Privacy Policy only addresses activities from our servers.

* ## Information Collection & Use

### Registration

The Squarespace service requires a login in order to provide you with a personalized account. During our account registration process, we will collect a login name, password, and an email address from you. You must provide all of this information in order to obtain an account. After completing our registration form, you will receive a welcome email describing your new Squarespace account, and how to access that account.

### Account Subscriptions

If you choose to continue service with Squarespace via a paid account, Squarespace will collect personally identifiable information (credit card number, billing address, phone number) and keep this information on file in our secure server in order to process your recurring invoices. This information is only used to verify credit card authenticity, and issue invoices as per your service agreement. Upon discontinuation of Squarespace service, your information will be immediately destroyed on our billing system.

If we are unable to process your subscription for a given month, this information, along with your account information, may be used to contact you.

### Tell-A-Friend Tools

Squarespace provides a number of tools that will allow you to promote your website (or articles on your website) over email. Email addresses entered into these forms are not stored in our database, but may be stored in our system logs in text format to assist us in tracking down abusive users (users flooding the system), or using these tools for spamming. We will never contact addresses logged in this manner. The email sent through any of these mechanisms is a one time email only.

### Hosted websites

Users hosting websites with Squarespace are given tools that may ask you to optionally enter your email address when making comments on their website, or contacting them through their website. Since users on Squarespace can manipulate the HTML code on their site directly, there are opportunities available for a malicious user to inject code that would log your information before it reaches our system. In addition, once in our system, website owners will have the opportunity to review and modify any information entered into their website. Since we do not have full control over how members run their individual sites, this privacy policy does not apply to any hosted Squarespace website that you do not own. You should check that you trust the owner of a particular website before submitting personally identifiable information on that site.

### Server Logs

When accessing web pages on the Squarespace.com domain, Squarespace may log your IP address, access URL, time of access, browser type, and referral URL in order to provide us with internal information regarding site traffic statistics. This information may also be used to identify users who are using the service for spam or other activity that is deemed in conflict with our Terms of Service. This information is used in the aggregate, and is never linked back to any personally identifiable information.

* ## Uses of Information

Squarespace collects the aforementioned personally identifiable information in order to provide you with a service that allows you to maintain an online presence. Various features in our website management system will, at your discretion, display your name, or adjust the date and time of events based on your locale. The Squarespace Website Manager interface will always give you an option before any piece of your personally identifiable information is presented on your website, and situations where information will be published is made clear in various spots in the interface (for example, your name is tied to welcome emails you send out from our system, and notice of this is given to you within the interface for that tool).

Squarespace also uses information collected through its service to send out notifications regarding service related issues (such as maintenance periods, billing problems, account expirations, and other items that may impact service). We do not send contact information unless the matter is deemed urgent, and most communication will occur through your Squarespace Website Manager interface.

Information collected through our service logs is used only to identify potential cases of abuse and establish statistical information regarding website traffic. This statistical information is not aggregated in such a way that would identify any particular user of the system.

Squarespace, Inc. is the sole owner of information collected on http://www.squarespace.com/. Your information is never shared, leased or given to any third parties in ways other than disclosed in this privacy statement.

* ## Information Security

We store all user information in secure databases protected via a variety of industry-standard access controls. Secure passwords, SSL encryption, disk-based encryption, firewalls, and other measures are in place that help us protect your data. This data is accessed only for the purposes specified in this privacy statement.

If you have any questions about security on our website, you can review our hosting FAQ or send us a support request using our support system.

* ## Access to Personally Identifiable Information

### Changing Information

All information that Squarespace stores related to your account, including any subscription billing information, is accessible through your Squarespace Website Manager interface. You may use this interface to adjust your information at any time, and we encourage you to keep this information up to date so that your customer service requests and billing processes operate efficiently.

### Removing Information

To remove your personally identifiable information from our system, submit your account for deactivation. Your personal information will be removed immediately, though your actual login name will remain reserved on our system until re-collection. If you wish to only remove your billing subscription information, cancel your paid account. Both of these removals can be accessed through your Squarespace Website Manager interface.

* ## Communications from Squarespace, Inc.

### Service-related Announcements

We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account.

### Customer Service

Upon issuing a customer support request to Squarespace, we may use your information and email address to contact you regarding your inquiry.

* ## Information Sharing and Disclosure

### Aggregate Information (non-personally identifiable)

We share aggregated demographic information about our user base with our advertisers. This information does not identify individual users. This information contains statistics related to traffic and the geographic location of our customers.

We do not link aggregate user data with personally identifiable information.

* ## Agents

### Credit Card Processing

We will submit your billing information to our credit card processing agent for approval when you update your billing information, or place an order on our website. This company does not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any purpose other than billing.

* ## Choice/Opt-out

Only non-promotional service announcements, as described in the above section, will be issued without prior authorization.

Upon deactivating your Squarespace account, you will receive no further communication from us (service announcements included).

* ## Log Files

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.

We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

We do not link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information.

* ## Cookies

Like most websites, we use small bits of data called cookies stored on users' computers to simulate a continuous connection. Cookies let us 'remember' information about your preferences and passwords and allow you to move within our Service without reintroducing yourself. Members who disable cookies will not be able to use Squarespace's services, as they are required to maintain your login to our service within a browser session. Disabling cookies does not prevent you from accessing websites published under our system, though some features of those sites may be degraded.

These cookies can be tied back to personally identifiable information only in the event that you are logged in to our service. If you are logged in to our service, the cookies on your computer will uniquely identify your account within our system.

This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by Squarespace, Inc. only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers. See the 'Third Party Advertisers' section for more details.

Some of our business partners (e.g., advertisers) use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies. See Third Party Advertisers.

* ## Third Party Advertisers

The ads appearing on this website are delivered to users by Google, our advertising partner. We do not share your personally identifiable information with Google to deploy these advertisements.

For more information related to Google advertisements, [please click here](http://www.google.com/).

* ## Bulletin Boards/Chat Rooms/Member Websites

If you use a bulletin board or chat room on this site, or on any Squarespace member website, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums.

Certain information, such as your name and ip address are logged by our system when posting messages, and are made available to the owner of the website you are posting on. These items may be displayed to readers of the site you are posting on, depending on the settings of that particular site. If you would not like to have these details disclosed, refrain from posting messages to any Squarespace bulletin board or chat room.

* ## Links to Other Sites

This website contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by Squarespace, Inc. Please be aware that we, Squarespace, Inc., are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites.

We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information.

This privacy statement applies only to information collected by this website.

* ## Business Transitions

In the event Squarespace, Inc. goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via email of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information.

* ## Legal Disclaimer

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our website.

* ## Changes in this Privacy Statement

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice within your Squarespace Website Manager interface.

* ## Contact Us

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us by using our support system.

Squarespace is located at:

Squarespace Inc.  
250 W. Broadway  
4th Floor  
New York, NY 10013 

**All correspondence** should be sent to:

Squarespace Inc.  
RE: Privacy Concern  
P.O. Box 1875  
New York, NY 10113
